<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Minnesota Department of Natural Resources (MNDNR)</origin>
        <pubdate>20030904</pubdate>
        <title>Scientific and Natural Area Units</title>
        <pubinfo>
          <publish>MNDNR - Division of Ecological and Water Resources, Scientific &amp; Natural Areas (SNA) Program</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>http://gisdata.mn.gov/dataset/bdry-scientific-and-nat-areas</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This dataset includes the main MNDNR Scientific and Natural Areas (SNA) feature class, along with ancillary feature classes such as annotation and parking lots.  These feature classes support MNNR's SNA Work Planning application.

scientific_and_natural_area_boundaries: A polygon feature class delineated on and digitized from 1:24,000 U.S.G.S. quad maps of Minnesota Scientific and Natural Areas (SNAs).

Scientific and natural areas are established to protect and perpetuate in an undisturbed natural state those lands and waters embracing natural features of exceptional scientific and educational value. The SNA Program's goal is to ensure that no single rare feature is lost from any region of the state. This requires protection and management of each feature in sufficient quantity and distribution across the landscape. The Programs' Long Range Plan is to protect at least five locations of plant communities known to occur in each landscape region, and three locations per region of each rare species, plant or animal, and geologic feature. It is estimated that 500 natural areas are needed throughout the state to adequately protect significant features. Because over 40 percent of these rare features occur in prairies, 200 SNAs would be in the prairie area of the state. Of the remainder, approximately 135 are estimated to be needed in the deciduous and 165 in coniferous forest landscape communities in the next 100 years. Protection of multiple sites in each landscape region is a vital means of capturing the genetic diversity and preventing the loss of important species, communities, and features. This strategy observes the wisdom of not putting all our eggs in one basket. 

In addition to SNA, Itasca and Crow Wing Counties have established county natural areas. Itasca County's natural areas were established in 1966. Sites are set aside as SNAs because of their natural attributes and rare resources, which warrant protection for their inherent values and as places for scientific and educational use. Protection guards against developments such as trails, campgrounds, picnic sites, logging, mineral exploration and development, cultivation, and other uses of land, public or private, that interfere with the preservation of its natural features</abstract>
      <purpose>To provide a multi-part polygon view of SNA Units for use in the SNA Work Planning - Activities application.

The original purpose for digitizing SNAs was to include them on the Minnesota County Biological Survey's maps of natural communities and rare species. This began in 1989. The Peatland SNAs were digitized 1993 for the generation of a series of maps showing existing trails withing these SNAs. Many prairie SNAs with burn units were digitized in 1995-6 for management purposes. The remaining SNAs were digitized in 1996-99 to complete the SNA cover statewide.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>20151113</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Time Period of Content date indicates the date which the user can be confident of accuracy and completeness of the dataset.</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Bi-Yearly</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-96.594773</westbc>
        <eastbc>-89.922535</eastbc>
        <northbc>48.995304</northbc>
        <southbc>43.455332</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekey>boundaries, SNA, Scientific and Natural Areas, Rare Plant Communities, boundaries, managed areas</themekey>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Category</themekt>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekey>Minnesota, MN</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>Use of the data are constrained only by the DNR GIS Data License Agreement. See the Distribution Liability section below for a link.</useconst>
    <browse>
      <browsen>ftp://ftp.gisdata.mn.gov/pub/gdrs/data/pub/us_mn_state_dnr/bdry_scientific_and_nat_areas/preview/preview.jpg</browsen>
    </browse>
    <crossref>
      <citeinfo>
        <title>
          </title>
      </citeinfo>
    </crossref>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntorg>Minnesota DNR - Division of Ecological Services</cntorg>
          <cntper>Tom Glancy</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>ECO Info Technology Supervisor</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical</addrtype>
          <address>500 Lafayette Road</address>
          <city>St. Paul</city>
          <state>MN</state>
          <postal>55155</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>651-259-5097</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>tom.glancy@state.mn.us</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <logic>Polygon(s) are coincident, verified closed, and intersect where intended.</logic>
    <complete>The data are statewide. Most of the SNA polygons were delineated on and digitized from 1:24,000 USGS quad maps over a period of more than 10 years. Newer SNA additions were digitized in ArcView GIS 3.x, based on 1:24,000 USGS Digital Raster Graphics (DRGs) with additional reference to USGS and National Agriculture Imagery Program (NAIP) aerial photogrphy.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>Unknown.  The coverage should be reasonably accurate although the boundaries probably will not line up with other public land survey information.
</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>Not Applicable
</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>This dataset of SNA boundaries is based on the SNA_BASE_DATA feature class in the MNDNR's core GIS Library. It includes only DEDICATED features, which are dissolved on the following attributes: SITENAME, SITE_ID, BREMCODE.

sna_parking: A point feature class of parking areas for Minnesota Scientific and Natural Areas. Utilize it for guidance to the designated place(s) to park when visiting a site. It was created in ArcMap10 using the following layers: SNA boundary layer, Department of Transportation (DOT) roads (All Classes), State Forest Roads, County Boundaries, Water Accesses and aerial photography from 1991, 2008, and 2009. SNA Regional Staff reviewed and edited layer. Google Earth was also used for some verifications.</procdesc>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>Attributes are checked during data entry process</attraccr>
    </attracc>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Not Applicable</indspref>
    <direct>vector</direct>
    <mgmg3obj>polygon</mgmg3obj>
    <mgmg3til>state</mgmg3til>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <vertdef>
      <altsys>
        <altdatum>Not Applicable</altdatum>
        <altunits>Not Applicable</altunits>
      </altsys>
      <depthsys>
        <depthdn>Not Applicable</depthdn>
        <depthdu>Not Applicable</depthdu>
      </depthsys>
    </vertdef>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
          <utm>
            <utmzone>15</utmzone>
          </utm>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>NAD83</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS80</ellips>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>scientific_and_natural_area_boundaries</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SITE_NAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of SNA Site</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SITE_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Numeric ID corresponding to the site name.</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>BREMCODE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Bureau of Real Estate Management (BREM) Code. This code references the corresponding entry for this site in the DNR Land Records system.</attrdef>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>sna_parking</enttypl>
        <enttypd>designated places to park for SNAs</enttypd>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PGRM_PROJE</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DIRECTIONS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>How to find the parking location</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Notes</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Further details about the parking location</attrdef>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <resdesc>bdry_scientific_and_nat_areas</resdesc>
    <distliab>The Minnesota Department of Natural Resources General Geographic Data License Agreement is online: http://www.dnr.state.mn.us/sitetools/data_software_license.html
</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <ordering>Please visit the download page for this dataset on the Minnesota Geospatial Commons website using the web link below (Online Linkage).</ordering>
    </stdorder>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntorg>Minnesota Department of Natural Resources</cntorg>
          <cntper>Zeb Thomas</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>GIS Data Systems Coordinator</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical</addrtype>
          <address>500 Lafayette Rd</address>
          <city>St. Paul</city>
          <state>MN</state>
          <postal>55155-4011</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>651-259-5637</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>zeb.thomas@state.mn.us</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>2014-09-26 01:00:35</metd>
    <metstdn>Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines</metstdn>
    <metstdv>1.2</metstdv>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/committee/standards/mgmg/metadata.htm</onlink>
    </metextns>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntorg>Minnesota Department of Natural Resources</cntorg>
          <cntper>Zeb Thomas</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>GIS Data Systems Coordinator</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical</addrtype>
          <address>500 Lafayette Rd</address>
          <city>St. Paul</city>
          <state>MN</state>
          <postal>55155-4011</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>651-259-5637</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>zeb.thomas@state.mn.us</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
