<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Minnesota Geospatial Information Office (MnGeo)</origin>
<pubdate>1972</pubdate>
<title>Land Use, Minnesota, 1969</title>
<mgmg1cid/>
<pubinfo>
<publish>Minnesota Geospatial Information Office (MnGeo)</publish>
</pubinfo>
<onlink>https://gisdata.mn.gov/dataset/biota-landcover-mlmis-1969</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>One of the original Minnesota Land Management Information System (MLMIS) data sets created in the 1970's, this dataset describes the state's land use patterns in 1969. Nine land use/land cover classes, interpreted from high altitude air photos, are recorded for each 40-acre parcel in the state. These classes include: forested; cultivated; water; marsh; urban residential; extractive; pasture and open; urban non-residential or mixed residential; and transportation.  MLMIS data sets were created by grid cell coding a value for each 40-acre parcel in the state. The file was later subdivided into 100-meter by 100-meter grid cells and spatially corrected to provide improved geographic reference. However, this processing step does not improve on the 40-acre resolution of the original data set.</abstract>
<purpose>The data set was designed for use in regional and statewide planning, not for site-specific decision making.</purpose>
<supplinf>Minnesota</supplinf>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>1969</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<current>Land use/cover interpretation is based primarily on air photos. Photo dates: the state south of St. Cloud was flown in April 1968;  the northern half of the state was flown in April 1969. Secondary source: Minnesota Department of Transportation County Highway Map Series (c.1968).</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>Complete</progress>
<update>None Planned</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>-97.25</westbc>
<eastbc>-89.48</eastbc>
<northbc>49.40</northbc>
<southbc>43.50</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
<themekey>Biota, imageryBaseMapsEarthCover, PlanningCadastre, land use, land cover, vegetation cover</themekey>
</theme>
<place>
<placekey>Minnesota</placekey>
</place>
</keywords>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>There are no restrictions on the use of these data. Data use should be consistent with the source, scale, and data capture methods.Redistribution Conditions: In obtaining these data from MnGeo, it is understood that you and/or your organization have the right to use it for any purpose. If you modify it, you are encouraged to apply responsible best practices by documenting those changes in a metadata record. If you transmit or provide the data to another user, it is your responsibility to provide appropriate content, limitation, warranty and liability information as you see fit.  </useconst>
<browse>
<browsen>ftp://ftp.gisdata.mn.gov/pub/gdrs/data/pub/us_mn_state_mngeo/biota_landcover_mlmis_1969/metadata/preview.jpg</browsen>
<browsed>A thumbnail graphic showing the statewide data.</browsed>
</browse>
<native>EPPL7</native>
<crossref>
<citeinfo>
<title>For information on other land use and land cover data available for Minnesota, see  http://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/chouse/land_use.html </title>
</citeinfo>
</crossref>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntperp>
<cntorg>Minnesota Geospatial Information Office (MnGeo)</cntorg>
<cntper>Nancy Rader</cntper>
</cntperp>
<cntpos>GIS Data Coordinator</cntpos>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>Mailing and Physical</addrtype>
<address>658 Cedar Street, Room 300</address>
<city>St. Paul</city>
<state>MN</state>
<postal>55155</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>651-201-2489</cntvoice>
<cntemail>gisinfo.mngeo@state.mn.us</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<attracc>
<attraccr>It is important to recognize that the classification scheme uses two different criteria:  dominant economic activity (use) and dominant spatial area (cover) to determine the class of any 40-acre parcel.  Spatial dominance was confined to the undeveloped (in terms of structures) land classes and generally refers to cover type.  The developed classes are determined by dominant economic activity.  Both urban categories and some transportation types supersede other cover types and urban mixed will supersede all other classes except airports and railyards in the transportation category.</attraccr>
</attracc>
<logic>Not applicable</logic>
<complete>Complete</complete>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>MLMIS data sets were created by grid cell coding a value for each 40-acre parcel in the state. The file was later subdivided into 100-meter by 100-meter grid cells and spatially corrected to provide improved geographic reference. However, this processing step does not improve on the 40-acre resolution of the original data set.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
<vertacc>
<vertaccr>Not applicable</vertaccr>
</vertacc>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<srcinfo>
<srcscale/>
</srcinfo>
<procstep>
<procdesc>In 1969, the Minnesota Land Management Information System (MLMIS), then located at the University of Minnesota, began to develop the original MLMIS40 statewide database. The MLMIS40 database recorded resource characteristics for every 40-acre parcel of land in the state using the Public Land Survey system (PLSS) as the reference system. The MLMIS40 database used the EPPL format developed specifically for that project.The primary information source for the land use file was 1:90,000-scale air photos from black and white panchromatic film.  The state south of St. Cloud was flown in April 1968 and the northern half in April 1969.  In both cases, the flights were flown east-to-west with flight lines about 10 miles apart.  Current county highway maps (c.1968), which at that time indicated such cultural features as individual houses, were used as a secondary source.Much of the original data entry was done with the classic grid-cell overlay technique. Each square, or raster, represented a 40-acre parcel creating a statewide database of about 1.4 million cells. By the late 1980s, the need for more detailed data for local GIS applications led to the development of MLMIS100, a new data standard with a finer spatial resolution. The MLMIS100 county data set is the geocorrected 100-meter resolution version of the MLMIS40 statewide data set. 1. EPPL 40-ACRE CODING PROCEDURE:  Land use/land cover interpretations were made at the University of Minnesota by a team of students headed by a professional photo-interpreter.  The data were coded by a recorder as the photo was being interpreted by a team of two.  Each township was covered by a mylar overlay with section lines delineated.  Each section was normally subdivided into sixteen 40-acre parcels.  Actual roads and field lines were used to identify 40-acre parcels on the ground; the grid was used where no visible boundaries occurred.2. GEOCORRECTION TO EPPL 100-METER DATA: In 1993, as part of the EPPL7/EPIC development project at the Land Management Information Center (LMIC, now MnGeo), a new data standard was created for use with raster GIS. The MGC100 (MLMIS Geocorrect 100 meter) state land use data set was created by appending all the MLMIS100 county land use data files together.  The 100-M layer retains the characteristics and resolution of the original 40-acre file.3. CONVERSION TO NAD83: In January 1998, the MGC100 data set was converted from NAD27 to NAD83 datum. GIS specialists and programmers from MN Department of Natural Resources, the Board of Water and Soil Resources, and LMIC cooperatively developed a standardized conversion process. It was determined that the difference between the two datums was small enough across any arbitrary area in Minnesota that it was sufficient to shift the files by the difference between NAD27 and NAD83. This procedure was adequate for the conversion of vector data sets but it caused cell mismatches when mosaicking raster data sets. Therefore, in order to create a uniform raster data set, LMIC shifted the EPPL7 files by adjusting the file extents to a multiple of the cell size, such that the actual cell size matched the nominal one, i.e. 100-meter data was made to be exactly 100 meters, with the edge of the file on 100-meter boundaries. Next, the 100-meter data was adjusted by 2 cells (200 meters) in the y direction. There was no need to adjust the files in the x direction because the difference between NAD27 and NAD83 datums is generally less than 10 meters.4. CONVERSION TO ERDAS AND GEOTIFF FORMATS: ERDAS and GeoTIFF formats were created from the EPPL file using the EPPL Export functions.5.  CONVERSION TO SHAPEFILE FORMAT:  ESRI Shapefile format was created from the EPPL file using the EPPL Export functions. </procdesc>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<indspref>None</indspref>
<direct>Raster</direct>
<mgmg3obj>Cell</mgmg3obj>
<mgmg3til>State</mgmg3til>
</spdoinfo>
<spref>
<vertdef>
<altsys>
<altdatum>not applicable</altdatum>
<altunits>Not applicable</altunits>
</altsys>
<depthsys>
<depthdn>not applicable</depthdn>
<depthdu>Not applicable</depthdu>
</depthsys>
</vertdef>
<horizsys>
<planar>
<gridsys>
<gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
<utm>
<utmzone>15E</utmzone>
</utm>
</gridsys>
<planci>
<plandu>meters</plandu>
<coordrep>
<absres>100</absres>
<ordres>100</ordres>
</coordrep>
</planci>
</planar>
<geodetic>
<horizdn>NAD83</horizdn>
<ellips>GRS80</ellips>
</geodetic>
</horizsys>
</spref>
<eainfo>
<overview>
<eaover>The nine land use/land cover classification codes are:1  Forested - A forty-acre parcel in which the dominant land use consists of trees.  To be considered forested, a forty must contain a scattering of trees whose crowns cover at least 10 percent of the land area.2  Cultivated - A forty-acre parcel in which the dominant use is land which has been recently tilled or harvested mechanically.3  Water - A forty-acre parcel in which the dominant land use is open and permanent water.4  Marsh - A forty-acre parcel in which the dominant land use consists of non-forested, shallow, permanently wet, vegetated areas.5  Urban Residential - A forty-acre parcel containing five or more residential dwellings, and commercial buildings.6  Extractive - A forty-acre parcel in which the dominant land use consists of the extraction of minerals, including ancillary facilities.  Examples are mines, tailing piles, gravel pits.7  Pasture and Open - A forty-acre parcel on non-forested land not used for any identifiable purpose.  Examples are grazing land or abandoned farm land.8  Urban Non-Residential or Mixed Residential Development - A forty-acre parcel containing at least one commercial, industrial, or institutional facility (including golf courses and cemeteries). It may or may not contain residential development.9  Transportation - A forty-acre parcel in which the dominant land use consists of facilities for the conveyance of people or materials.</eaover>
<eadetcit>'MGC100 Data Documentation', formerly called 'Data Documentation for 40-Acre and 100-Meter Data for Use with EPPL7 on IBM PCs, PS/2s, or Compatibles'. Land Management Information Center, Minnesota Planning. 1998.  'MGC100: Revisiting MLMIS40 Raster Data in 16-bit', by Thomas G. Eiber, Les Maki, and Ken Pekarek. This paper was presented at the 1996 Minnesota GIS/LIS Conference held September 25-27, 1996 in St. Louis Park, MN. These documents are included with the standard metadata for the dataset.</eadetcit>
</overview>
</eainfo>
<distinfo>
<resdesc>luse69</resdesc>
<distliab>MnGeo's data disclaimer is online: http://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/chouse/disclaimer.html</distliab>
<stdorder>
<digform>
<digtinfo>
<formname>EPPL7, ERDAS, GeoTIFF, shapefile</formname>
<formvern>3.0</formvern>
<transize>10 MB as self-extracting zipfile; 2.9 MB EPPL7 format; 36.7 MB ERDAS format; 3.1 MB GeoTIFF format; 29.3 MB shapefile format.</transize>
</digtinfo>
</digform>
<ordering>Download available formats via the Minnesota Geospatial Commons. </ordering>
</stdorder>
<distrib>
<cntinfo>
<cntperp>
<cntorg>Minnesota Geospatial Information Office (MnGeo)</cntorg>
<cntper>Nancy Rader</cntper>
</cntperp>
<cntpos>GIS Data Coordinator</cntpos>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
<address>658 Cedar Street, Room 300</address>
<city>St. Paul</city>
<state>MN</state>
<postal>55155</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>651-201-2489</cntvoice>
<cntemail>gisinfo.mngeo@state.mn.us</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</distrib>
</distinfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20150206</metd>
<metstdn>Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines</metstdn>
<metstdv>1.2</metstdv>
<metextns>
<onlink>http://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/committee/standards/mgmg/metadata.htm</onlink>
</metextns>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntperp>
<cntorg>Minnesota Geospatial Information Office (MnGeo)</cntorg>
<cntper>Nancy Rader</cntper>
</cntperp>
<cntpos>GIS Data Coordinator</cntpos>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
<address>658 Cedar Street, Room 300</address>
<city>St. Paul</city>
<state>MN</state>
<postal>55155</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>651-201-2489</cntvoice>
<cntemail>gisinfo.mngeo@state.mn.us</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
